<task>
  <id>0011</id>
  <status>open</status>
  <priority>P1</priority>
  <title>Finish higher-order whitespace normalization gaps exposed by floating fixtures</title>
  <summary>
    The first whitespace-normalization pass fixed the checked-in regressions, but
    eight real fixtures still show stable post-format residue in higher-order
    shapes such as statement joining, interpolation spacing, and multiline string
    body handling.
  </summary>
  <problem>
    After re-running `nuparu --write` against the intentionally dirtied fixture
    corpus, the remaining diffs are no longer broad indentation noise. They are
    concentrated in a smaller set of semantic-looking formatting failures:
    neighboring commands still collapse onto one line in a few control-flow and
    reporting shapes, repeated spaces survive inside interpolated strings and
    regex-like literals where they should probably collapse, and embedded
    multiline string bodies are being normalized when they appear to need
    verbatim preservation. These cases are visible directly in the floating
    fixture diffs and should disappear as the formatter implementation improves.
  </problem>
  <affectedFiles>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/configure-apps.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/lima-ports.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/upgrade-workflows.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scrubs/bootstrap.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scrubs/download-latest-iso.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scrubs/seed.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scrubs/sync-base-image-from-icloud.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scrubs/sync-base-image-to-icloud.nu</file>
  </affectedFiles>
  <relatedCode>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/__tests__/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>tasks/review/0010-normalize-whitespace-noise-in-fixtures.xml</path>
  </relatedCode>
  <acceptanceCriteria>
    <criterion>Whitespace-only noise does not collapse distinct neighboring commands like adjacent function calls, `print` plus `return`, or sequential setup commands onto the same line in the remaining fixture shapes.</criterion>
    <criterion>Repeated spaces inside interpolated strings, regex-like string arguments, and similar inline string-bearing constructs are either normalized intentionally or preserved intentionally, with a clear rule that matches the desired style.</criterion>
    <criterion>Embedded multiline string bodies that represent foreign source text or shell scripts are preserved verbatim enough that formatter cleanup outside the string does not rewrite their internal spacing and indentation.</criterion>
    <criterion>The floating fixture diffs for these eight files disappear after formatting, and any new regression tests added for them are derived from the observed fixture residue.</criterion>
  </acceptanceCriteria>
</task>
