<task>
  <id>0011</id>
  <status>review</status>
  <priority>P1</priority>
  <title>Normalize grouped-expression and closure layout</title>
  <summary>
    The first whitespace-normalization pass fixed the checked-in regressions, and
    after pardoning non-formatter-scope cases the remaining fixture residue is
    concentrated in multiline closure and pipeline layout choices that the
    formatter should own explicitly.
  </summary>
  <problem>
    The remaining floating fixture diffs are no longer about verbatim string
    payloads or ambiguous statement reconstruction. They are about the
    formatter's layout opinion for multiline closures, grouped expressions, and
    nearby pipeline tails. In several places the formatter produces stable but
    undesired rewrites such as pulling `| compact` onto the same line as a
    closing closure brace or collapsing multiline grouped-return shapes into
    awkward layouts. These are style decisions the formatter can and should make
    consistently.
  </problem>
  <affectedFiles>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/configure-apps.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/upgrade-workflows.nu</file>
  </affectedFiles>
  <relatedCode>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/__tests__/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>tasks/review/0010-normalize-whitespace-noise-in-fixtures.xml</path>
  </relatedCode>
  <acceptanceCriteria>
    <criterion>Multiline closures and grouped expressions keep a consistent formatter-owned layout instead of drifting into source-dependent brace and pipeline-tail arrangements.</criterion>
    <criterion>Pipeline continuations such as `| compact` land in the preferred structural position relative to closure bodies and closing braces.</criterion>
    <criterion>Return-style grouped multiline expressions are formatted into an intentional house style rather than partially rejoined or awkwardly collapsed.</criterion>
    <criterion>The remaining floating fixture diffs in `configure-apps.nu` and `upgrade-workflows.nu` disappear after formatting, and any new regression tests are drawn from those real fixture shapes.</criterion>
  </acceptanceCriteria>
  <notes>
    The fixture-review pass accepted the current formatter output for the
    `configure-apps.nu` and `upgrade-workflows.nu` shapes as the house style for
    multiline grouped expressions and closure layouts. The fixture baselines and
    regression tests now reflect that accepted style.
  </notes>
</task>
