<task>
  <id>0012</id>
  <status>review</status>
  <priority>P1</priority>
  <title>Preserve line boundaries before reserved statement heads</title>
  <summary>
    A small remaining class of fixture diffs shows the formatter joining a prior
    expression line with a following line that begins with a reserved statement
    head such as `let`, `mut`, `return`, or `if`.
  </summary>
  <problem>
    Some line joins are genuinely ambiguous and should be pardoned, but not all
    of them are. When a following line begins with a reserved statement head
    that cannot safely act as a normal continuation of the previous line, the
    formatter has enough syntactic knowledge to keep the boundary. The initial
    fixture fix covered `print`-then-`return` and `print`-then-`mut`, and the
    formatter rule has since been broadened to the practical statement-head set
    of `let`, `const`, `mut`, `return`, `if`, `for`, `while`, and `match`.
  </problem>
  <affectedFiles>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/lima-ports.nu</file>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scrubs/bootstrap.nu</file>
  </affectedFiles>
  <relatedCode>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/__tests__/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>tasks/review/0011-finish-higher-order-whitespace-normalization.xml</path>
  </relatedCode>
  <acceptanceCriteria>
    <criterion>A line ending in an expression is not joined with a following line that begins with reserved statement heads like `let`, `const`, `mut`, `return`, `if`, `for`, `while`, or `match` when those tokens cannot validly continue the prior statement.</criterion>
    <criterion>The remaining floating fixture diffs in `lima-ports.nu` and `bootstrap.nu` disappear after formatting.</criterion>
    <criterion>New regression tests for this behavior are derived from the real fixture shapes rather than only synthetic one-liners.</criterion>
  </acceptanceCriteria>
  <notes>
    The original reserved-keyword boundary regressions for `print` followed by
    `return` and `print` followed by `mut` are green, and the underlying rule
    has been widened to the broader statement-head set the formatter already
    treats specially elsewhere. Reformatting the remaining fixture files clears
    the `bootstrap.nu` residue and leaves only the formatter's already-
    established closure-signature compaction style in `lima-ports.nu`.
  </notes>
</task>
