<task>
  <id>0015</id>
  <status>review</status>
  <priority>P2</priority>
  <title>Honor line width when compacting multiline pipelines</title>
  <summary>
    The formatter should decide whether to collapse a multiline pipeline based
    on the configured line width, not simply on whether one adjacent stage can
    be rejoined.
  </summary>
  <problem>
    In `lima-ports.nu`, a multiline pipeline inside the `else` branch currently
    reforms from:
    `ls $lima_dir`
    `| where type == dir`
    into `ls $lima_dir | where type == dir` while the remaining stages stay on
    later lines. That creates an inconsistent half-compacted shape. The desired
    policy is: if the fully collapsed pipeline fits within the configured line
    width, the formatter should collapse it to one line; if the fully collapsed
    pipeline would exceed the line width, the formatter should preserve the
    multiline shape instead of collapsing only the head upward. This is not the
    same problem as restoring a broken operator continuation like `where type`
    followed by `== dir`; it is a layout decision about compacting or
    preserving the entire pipeline.
  </problem>
  <affectedFiles>
    <file>fixtures/dotfiles/scripts/lima-ports.nu</file>
  </affectedFiles>
  <relatedCode>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>crates/nuparu-core/src/__tests__/formatter.rs</path>
    <path>tasks/review/0014-rejoin-tight-continuations-and-delimiter-adjacency.xml</path>
  </relatedCode>
  <acceptanceCriteria>
    <criterion>Multiline pipelines collapse to a single line when the fully joined form fits within the configured line width.</criterion>
    <criterion>Multiline pipelines remain multiline when the fully joined form would exceed the configured line width.</criterion>
    <criterion>The formatter does not produce half-compacted pipeline shapes where only the head stage collapses upward while later stages remain on separate lines.</criterion>
    <criterion>The formatter still restores genuinely broken operator continuations like `where type` followed by `== dir` when that is the actual residue.</criterion>
    <criterion>Regression coverage includes the real `lima-ports.nu` fixture shape and a line-width-sensitive collapse case.</criterion>
  </acceptanceCriteria>
</task>
